Guide to the William Hewlett Papers M1995
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 17: Addenda 2016-122, 1907-2010
  - Comet Halley, 1985-1986: A portfolio of images obtained at the Las Campanas Observatory of the Carnegie Institution of Washington. Presented to William R. Hewlett (Flat-box 5, Item 3)
  - Story of a Little Boy, Louise Redington Hewlett Published by Hewlett Family Library, 1994-2005 (Box 710, Folder 9)
  - Photographs: William R. Hewlett Silhouette by Newton of Sacramento, 1933 (Carton 5, Item 2)
  - Flowers Along the Trail: Wildflower Images from the Sierra and Coastal Mountains of California, William R. Hewlett, Hewlett-Packard Company, 1999 (Flat-box 7, Item 1)
  - Flower Collection Project (HP Labs), 1991-1998 (Box 710, Folder 10)
  - Hewlett-Packard: Lab Notes: Special 50th Anniversary Edition, January/June, 1999 (Flat-box 8, Item 1)
  - Hewlett-Packard: Photographs of William R. Hewlett's Office, undated (Flat-box 8, Item 2)
  - Hewlett-Packard: Posters, 1995-1999 (Flat-box 8, Item 3)
  - Hewlett-Packard: Schematic of Audio Oscillator 200A, 1939 (Flat-box 8, Item 4)
  - Jacobsen, Barbara Ann: Memorial Service, 2007 (Box 710, Folder 11)
    Barbara Ann Jacobsen was an employee at the San Felipe Ranch.
  - Newspaper Collection, 1930-1969 (Flat-box 9, Folder 1)
  - Packard, David: Measure Magazine Memorial, 1996 (Box 710, Folder 12)
  - Packard, David: Memorial Programs, 1996 (Box 710, Folder 13)
  - Packard, David: Obituaries, 1996 (Flat-box 6, Folder 4)
  - Scattered Leaves: Album of Leaves, undated (Flat-box 10, Item 1)
  - Scattered Leaves: Correspondence About the Publication, 1991-1998 (Box 710, Folder 14)
  - Scattered Leaves: Leaves from the Bohemian Grove, William R. Hewlett, William R. Hewlett Family Library, 1998 (Flat-box 10, Item 2)
  - Scattered Leaves: Leaves from the Bohemian Grove, William R. Hewlett, William R. Hewlett Family Library, Master: Second Edition, 1998 (Flat-box 10, Item 3)
  - Scattered Leaves: Proof Sheets from Press Color Checks, 1998 (Map-folder 17, Item 1)
  - Scattered Leaves: Proof Sheets, undated (Flat-box 11, Folder 1)
  - Schroeder, Friedrich W: Interview, undated (Box 710, Folder 15)
    Frierich W. Schroeder was the General Manager of Hewlett-Packard Germany.
  - Stanford University: Donations, 1994-2001 (Flat-box 6, Folder 5)
  - Taking Time to Stop and Look: A Guide to Flora at the Bohemian Grove, William R. Hewlett, The William R. Hewlett Family Library, 2008 (Box 711, Folder 1)
  - Taking Time to Stop and Look: A Guide to Flora at the Cedars, William R. Hewlett, The William R. Hewlett Family Library, 2009 (Box 711, Folder 2)
  - The Flora Family Foundation: The Early Years, 1998-2003, Herant Katchadourian, Flora Family Foundation, 2004 (Box 711, Folder 3)
  - Report of Trip to the Pacific Theaters of Operation (part 1 of 2), 1944 (Box 711, Folder 4)
    Report of August 1944 trip to Pacific theaters of operation by Major William R. Hewlett for the purpose of determining the operational performance of Army signal equipment in the Pacific theater.
  - Report of Trip to the Pacific Theaters of Operation (part 2 of 2), 1944 (Box 711, Folder 5)
  - Report on Scientific Intelligence Survey in Japan, Volume I, 1945 (Box 711, Folder 6)
    Report on Scientific Intelligence Survey in Japan from September-November, 1945. "Covering interviews and other material relating to Japanese Army and Navy research and development on instruments and equipment."
  - Report on Scientific Intelligence Survey in Japan, Volume II, 1945 (Box 711, Folder 7)
  - Eta Kappa Nu Assocation's Certificate of Eminent Membership, 1999 (Box 712, Folder 3)
  - "How Hewlett-Packard beat the Corporate Bloat That Choaked IBM and DEC", Forbes, 1993 (Box 712, Folder 4)
  - Inventions of Opportunity: Matching Technology with Market Needs, introduction by William R. Hewlett, Hewlett-Packard Company, 1983 (Box 712, Folder 5)
  - The Complete Woodblock Prints of Yoshida Hiroshi, Abe Publishing Company, 1987 (Box 712, Folder 6)
  - The HP Way: How Bill Hewlett and I Built Our Company, David Packard, Harper Collins (autographed by David Packard and William R. Hewlett), 1995 (Box 712, Folder 7)
  - Report on Scientific Intelligence Survey in Japan, Volume III, 1945 (Box 711, Folder 8)
  - William R. Hewlett Journal of U.S. Army Scientific Intelligence Survey in Japan, 1945 (Box 712, Folder 1)
    Handwritten journals from William R. Hewlett's U.S. Army Scientific Intelligence Survey trip to Japan in October and November of 1945. Includes itinerary, lists of items needed for trip, etc.
  - William R. Hewlett Notebook from Trip to the United Kingdom with Notes about European Trade for the Hewlett-Packard Company, 1954 (Box 712, Folder 2)
  - East Bay Community Foundation Plaque of Appreciation, 1988 (Carton 5, Item 3)
    To William R. Hewlett for challenge grants to East Bay Community Foundation at their 60th anniversary celebration at Oakland, California, March 22, 1988.
  - Military Insignia, 1941-1945 (Carton 5, Item 4)
  - Grade of Fellow Diploma, Institute of Radio Engineers, 1948 (Map-folder 16, Item 2)
  - Honorary Doctor of Electronics Degree, University of Bologna, 1989 (Carton 5, Item 5)
  - Honorary Doctor of Humanities Degree, Santa Clara University, 1991 (Map-folder 16, Item 3)
  - IEEE Millenium Medal, 2000 (Carton 5, Item 6)
  - Medal of Excellence Document, University of Brussels, 1995 (Map-folder 16, Item 4)
  - MVP Award Plaque to William R. Hewlett, undated (Carton 5, Item 7)
  - Plaque with Photograph of Ocean Going Vessel, Perhaps Carrying Copper Ore for Island Copper Company, undated (Carton 5, Item 8)
  - Republican Senatorial Inner Circle Lapel Pins, 1992 (Carton 5, Item 9)
  - University of Notre Dame Acknowledgement of Support to Willam R. Hewlett and Rosemary B. Hewlett, 1985-1990 (Carton 5, Item 10)
  - Vestment Garments from University of Bologna Honorary Doctorate Ceremony, 1989 (Carton 5, Item 11)
  - William R. Hewlett Distinguished Citizen Award in Display Box, 1977 (Carton 5, Item 12)
  - William R. Hewlett Engraved Printing Plate, undated (Carton 5, Item 13)
  - William R.Hewlett's Hewlett-Packard Company Name Badges and Retirement Badge, undated (Carton 5, Item 14)
  - HP-15c Calculator Keyboard (only), 1982-1989 (Carton 6, Item 1)
  - HP-55 Calculator, 1975 (Carton 6, Item 2)
    Name on front label reads, "Bill Hewlett" (William R. Hewlett's personal copy).
  - 16 Calculator Data Cartridges, 1985 (Carton 7, Cassette 1)
    Includes cartridges for HP-85, HP-200 etc. Cartridges contain magnetic tape storage media.
  - HP-01 Calculator Wrist Watch, 1977-1980 (Carton 6, Item 3)
    William R. Hewlett's personal copy. Includes gold case, snakeskin leather strap
  - HP-826026A "Woodstock" Two-Cell Calculator Battery Pack Charger and AC Adapter, 1975 (Carton 6, Item 4)
    For HP calculators 21-29 series.
  - HP Photosmart Digital Camera Prototype (C5340A) with computer cables, software CD and manual, 1997 (Carton 6, Item 5)
  - HP-28c Calculator, 1987-1988 (Carton 6, Item 6)
  - HP-29c Calculator, 1977-1979 (Carton 6, Item 7)
  - HP-35 Calculator, 1972-1975 (Carton 6, Item 8)
    Serial No. 00317. Nameplate reads, "William R. Hewlett". Includes reproduced manual.
  - HP-80 Pocket Calculator, 1973-1978 (Carton 6, Item 9)
    Serial No. 03594. Nameplate reads, "William R. Hewlett".
  - Philips Miniature Tape Recorder (inside HP calculator shell), undated (Carton 6, Item 10)
  - HP-67 Calculator, 1976-1984 (Carton 6, Item 11)
    Serial No. 1610A01839. Calculator stores programs on magnetic insertable cards.
  - HP-15c Calculator, 1982-1989 (Carton 6, Item 12)
    Serial No. USA 2450A11025. "Scientific With Matrix & Complex Math" model. Includes silulated leather slip cover. Calculator is in working condition.
  - HP-14b Business Calculator, 1987 (Carton 6, Item 13)
    Serial No. 2813A03388. Algebraic business calculator, non-programmable.
  - HP-35c Calculator, 1972 (Carton 6, Item 14)
    Serial No. 08387. The HP-35 was HP's first pocket calculator. It was introduced at a time when most calculators (including expensive desktop models) had only the four basic functions. The HP-35 was the first pocket calculator with transcendental functions and the first with RPN (reverse polish notation).
  - HP-75c Calculator, 1982-1984 (Carton 6, Item 15)
    Serial No. USA 2241A00407. Unit contained in mock leather case with black metal nameplate reading, "William R. Hewlett". The HP-75c was HP's first portable computer. It ran BASIC, and came with 16K of RAM with an expansion port for additional RAM and 48K of ROM with 3 ROM expansion ports. It had a keyboard that was large enough to touch type on (about 95% of full size), a very readable one line alpha display and an HP-IL port that allowed it to be attached to almost anything.
  - HP Omnibook Model 300, 1993 (Carton 6, Item 16)
    Serial No. US31900385. Nameplate on bottom reads, "Bill Hewlett". Includes 2 plug-in cards: one memory card and one 10 meg memory card. Based on Intel 386 processor, features a full VGA monochrome LCD monitor. Runs Windows 3.1 from ROM.
  - Lightning Desktop Adding Machine (mechanical), 1908 (Carton 6, Item 17)
    The Lightning Adder was somewhat less expensive in construction than other similar units of its era and lacked a clearing mechanism. This machine required the user to clear each dial by rotating it to zero. It was introduced in 1908. The metal mechanical mechanism rests in a brown bakelite tray.
  - HP-82143A Peripheral Printer, 1980 (Carton 6, Item 18)
    Accessory for the HP-41c Calculator. Serial No. 1934A79764. Battery pack installed. "The 82143A is a battery-operated thermal printer capable of delivering 24 characters per line at a scan rate of 60 characters per second while acting as a peripheral device to the HP-41c Calculator system. The nominal line rate of the printer varies from 130 lines per minute for lines of 10 characters or less to 60 lines per minute for 34-character ines. Communication between the 82143A and the controlling HP-41c is accomplished through a seven-line serial interface."
  - HP-82240A Portable Thermal Printer, 1985 (Carton 6, Item 19)
    Serial No. 8652S10394. "This printer uses infrared technology to print information from several HP machines, including the 38G and 28S."
  - HP-11424A Optical Plummet (surveying tool), undated (Carton 6, Item 20)
    Contained in a square leather case marked with the HP logo.
  - HP-65 Calculator Magnetic Cards, 1974 (Carton 6, Item 21)
    Four packages. Each case contains 40 magnetic cards for storing calculator programs.
  - HP-82104A Calculator Card Reader, 1979-1985 (Carton 6, Item 22)
    Serial No. 1936A00385. "The 82104A card reader is for the HP-41 series of calculators."
  - Various Calculator Parts, undated (Carton 6, Item 23)
  - Various Leather Calculator Covers, undated (Carton 6, Item 24)
  - Various Calculator Manuals, undated (Carton 6, Item 25)
  - Money Owner's PAC 0077-82002 Rev. A Magnetic Strips, undated (Carton 6, Item 26)
  - Documentation: Dave Packard and Bill Hewlett (recorded in 1983, transferred from VHS), 2002 (Carton 7, Videodisc 1)
  - Documentation: Dave Packard and Bill Hewlett (recorded in 1983, transferred from VHS), 2002 (Carton 7, Videodisc 2)
  - Documentation: Dave Packard and Bill Hewlett (recorded in 1983, transferred from VHS), 2002 (Carton 7, Videodisc 3)
  - Films by William R. Hewlett, 1942-1962 (Carton 7, Videodisc 4)
  - Films by William R. Hewlett, 1942-1962 (Carton 7, Videodisc 5)
  - Hewlett Family Reunion, 1980 (Carton 7, Videodisc 6)
  - Hewlett Family Reunion, 1984 (Carton 7, Videodisc 7)
  - Hewlett Family Reunion, 1984 (Carton 7, Videodisc 8)
  - Hewlett Family Reunion, 1988 (Carton 7, Videodisc 9)
  - Hewlett Family Reunion, 1992 (Carton 7, Videodisc 10)
  - Hewlett-Lamson-Hughes Family Reunion, 2004 (Carton 7, Videodisc 11)
  - Highlights: Bill Hewlett's 35mm Slide Collection (undated), 2004 (Carton 7, Videodisc 12)
  - Highlights: Bill Hewlett's 35mm Slide Collection (undated), 2004 (Carton 7, Videodisc 13)
  - Highlights: Bill Hewlett's 35mm Slide Collection (undated), 2004 (Carton 7, Videodisc 14)
  - HP Employee Picnic (circa 1950s) (transferred from 8mm), 2004 (Carton 7, Videodisc 15)
  - Louise Hewlett Nixon Memorial Album, March 7, 2004 (Carton 7, Videodisc 16)
  - Party at Grandpa's, July 15, 1983 (Carton 7, Videodisc 17)
  - A Tribute to Bill Hewlett and Dave Packard by Bill Wedlock, 2003 (Carton 7, Videodisc 19)
  - San Felipe Ranch 50th Anniversary Slideshow, 2004 (Carton 7, Videodisc 18)
  - Walter B. Hewlett: Images DVD Slides Shows, 2004 (Carton 7, Videodisc 20)
  - William R. Hewlett: "Milestones" (1942-1962), 2002 (Carton 7, Videodisc 21)
  - William R. Hewlett: "Milestones" (1942-1962), 2002 (Carton 7, Videodisc 22)
  - William R. Hewlett: 65th Birthday Party, 1978 (Carton 7, Videodisc 23)
  - William R. Hewlett: 65th Birthday Party, 1978 (Carton 7, Videodisc 24)
  - William R. Hewlett's 80th Birthday Party, 1993 (Carton 7, Videodisc 25)
  - William R. Hewlett's 80th Birthday Party, 1993 (Carton 7, Videodisc 26)
  - Alan Nixon's Early Life. Interviewed by his daughter Sandra Nixon January (1998), 2003 (Carton 7, Compact disc 1)
  - Contents of 720 Los Trancos Road After Fire, 2001 (Carton 7, Compact disc 2)
  - Contents of 720 Los Trancos Road After Fire, 2001 (Carton 7, Compact disc 3)
  - Contents of 720 Los Trancos Road After Fire, 2001 (Carton 7, Compact disc 4)
  - Contents of 720 Los Trancos Road After Fire, 2001 (Carton 7, Compact disc 5)
  - Contents of 720 Los Trancos Road After Fire, 2001 (Carton 7, Compact disc 6)
  - Contents of 720 Los Trancos Road After Fire, 2001 (Carton 7, Compact disc 7)
  - Contents of 720 Los Trancos Road After Fire, 2001 (Carton 7, Compact disc 8)
  - Contents of 720 Los Trancos Road After Fire, 2001 (Carton 7, Compact disc 9)
  - Contents of 720 Los Trancos Road After Fire, 2001 (Carton 7, Compact disc 10)
  - Contents of 720 Los Trancos Road After Fire, 2001 (Carton 7, Compact disc 11)
  - Contents of 720 Los Trancos Road After Fire, 2001 (Carton 7, Compact disc 12)
  - Contents of 720 Los Trancos Road After Fire, 2001 (Carton 7, Compact disc 13)
  - Contents of 720 Los Trancos Road After Fire, 2001 (Carton 7, Compact disc 14)
  - Contents of 720 Los Trancos Road After Fire, 2001 (Carton 7, Compact disc 15)
  - Contents of 720 Los Trancos Road After Fire, 2001 (Carton 7, Compact disc 16)
  - Contents of 720 Los Trancos Road After Fire, 2001 (Carton 7, Compact disc 17)
  - HP/Agilent: HPL's Big Bash, October 20, 1999 (Carton 7, Compact disc 18)
  - Recordings of Jungle Sounds by the Division of Acoustical Research, Rutgers University (1945), 2005 (Carton 7, Compact disc 19)
  - Redington Ranch Map Disk, undated (Carton 7, Compact disc 20)
  - San Felipe Ranch Map Revisions, 2003 (Carton 7, Compact disc 21)
  - A Memorial Celebration of William R. Hewlett: Stanford Memorial Church, Stanford, California, January 20, 2001 (Carton 8, Videotape 1)
  - A Memorial Celebration of William R. Hewlett: Stanford Memorial Church, Stanford, California, January 20, 2001 (Carton 8, Videotape 2)
  - A Memorial Celebration of William R. Hewlett: Stanford Memorial Church, Stanford, California, January 20, 2001 (Carton 8, Videotape 3)
  - A Memorial Celebration of William R. Hewlett: Stanford Memorial Church, Stanford, California, January 20, 2001 (Carton 8, Videotape 4)
  - David Packard Memorial Service and Tributes, 1996 (Carton 8, Videotape 5)
  - David Packard Memorial Service and Tributes, 1996 (Carton 8, Videotape 6)
  - Hewlett - Schematic A (720 Los Trancos) D. McMullen AIA, undated (Carton 8, Videotape 7)
  - Hewlett-Packard "The Discovery", July 16, 1993 (Carton 8, Videotape 8)
  - Hewlett-Packard Documentation Parts 1 and 2, 1991 (Carton 8, Videotape 9)
  - Hewlett-Packard Documentation Parts 3 and 4, 1991 (Carton 8, Videotape 10)
  - Hewlett-Packard Story on CNBC, January 18, 1998 (Carton 8, Videotape 11)
  - Hewlett-Packard Video Magazine, 1987 (Carton 8, Videotape 12)
  - Living Legends: Bill and Dave's Story by Bell South, circa 1985 (Carton 8, Videotape 13)
  - Silicon Valley Boomtown, KTEH 54 San Jose, undated (Carton 8, Videotape 14)
  - William Hewlett Memorial Service, 2001 (Carton 8, Videotape 15)
  - William Hewlett Memorial Service, 2001 (Carton 8, Videotape 16)
  - William Hewlett Memorial Service, 2001 (Carton 8, Videotape 17)
- Series 18: Addenda 2017-274
  - Korea Trip, 1988 (Box 713, Folder 1)
  - Medical Technology Documents (Box 713, Folder 2)
  - American University of Beirut Documents (Box 713, Folder 3)
  - "Random Thoughts on Silicon Valley", 06-18-1992 (Box 713, Folder 4)
  - News Clippings, 1988 - 1989 (Box 713, Folder 5)
  - "Looking Ahead: A Presentation to the HP Interex User Group", 09-11-1989 (Box 713, Folder 6)
  - Assorted Misc. Documents, 1987 - 1992 (Box 713, Folder 7)
  - Bohemian Club (Membership) (Box 713, Folder 8)
  - Deuville Conference, Outside Materials, May 1967 (Box 713, Folder 9)
  - Ladbroke Hotels Materials (Box 713, Folder 10)
  - SF Symphony Documents (Box 713, Folder 11)
  - Rand Expense Accounts, 1968 - 1972 (Box 713, Folder 12)
  - WHOI Trustee Appointment (Box 713, Folder 13)
  - Stanford Trustees Reunion, April 9-11, 1989 (Box 713, Folder 14)
  - APS Philosophical Society General Meeting, Nov. 8-9, 1990 (Box 713, Folder 15)
  - Carnegie Institution Retirement Plan Statements, Sep. - Nov., 1982 and Jan. - Mar., 1983 (Box 713, Folder 16)
  - Carnegie Institution Trust Retirement Plan Statements, Sep. - Nov., 1982 and Jan. - Mar., 1983 (Box 713, Folder 17)
  - Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace, 1991 - 1992 (Box 713, Folder 18)
  - UCAR, 1987 - 1992 (Box 714, Folder 1)
  - CEPR Materials, 1989 - 1990 (Box 714, Folder 2)
  - AAAS Materials (Box 714, Folder 3)
  - IEEE Documents and William Hewlett Obituary (Box 714, Folder 4)
  - Utah International Materials (Box 714, Folder 5)
  - HP Product Gift Program for Educational Support (Box 714, Folder 6)
  - Foreign Currency Management Memo, 05/16/1985 (Box 714, Folder 7)
  - Beneficiary Designation, 07/01/1974 (Box 714, Folder 8)
  - Beckman Center Materials, 1986 - 1988 (Box 714, Folder 9)
  - California Academy of Sciences - Misc. Materials (Box 714, Folder 10)
  - MBARI Pamphlet (Box 714, Folder 11)
  - Public Policy Institute of California (Box 714, Folder 12-14)
  - Misc. Invoices and Receipts (Box 715, Folder 1)
  - "Criteria for Directors", 06-03-1976 (Box 715, Folder 2)
  - Assorted Misc. Public Policy Institute of California Materials (Box 715, Folder 3-4)
  - Menlo Country Club Candidate Sponsorship Procedure (Box 715, Folder 5)
  - World Affairs Council of Northern California 40th Anniversary Review (Box 715, Folder 6)
  - Bohemian Club Membership Dues (Box 715, Folder 7)
  - Dues, Memberships, and Subscriptions - Paid Bills (Box 715, Folder 8)
  - Washington - Chicago Schedule, 4/23 - 26/1974 (Box 715, Folder 9)
  - Menlo Country Club - Paid Bills (Box 715, Folder 10)
  - Carnegie Institution Materials (Box 715, Folder 11)
  - Howard Vollum Obituary - Tekweek, 02-05-1986 (Box 715, Folder 12)
  - Introduction to "Linear Electron Accelerators" by W.W. Hansen (Box 715, Folder 13)
  - Misc. Newspaper Clippings (Box 716, Folder 1)
  - Magellan Telescope Postcards (Box 716, Folder 2)
  - Institute of Radio Engineers Materials` (Box 716, Folder 3)
  - Chrysler Corporation Materials (Box 716, Folder 4)
  - NAS/NRC Materials (Box 716, Folder 5)
  - Barney Oliver's "Modern English Misusage" and SETI CEO Letter (Box 716, Folder 6)
  - Misc. Wildflower Photos, Slides, and Negatives (Box 716, Folder 7)
  - William Hewlett Flower Collection Listings and Indexes (Box 716, Folder 8)
  - Flower Collection Correspondence and Listings (Box 716, Folder 9)
  - Wildflower Photos, Slides, and Negatives (Box 716, Folder 10)
  - Scattered Leaves, 2nd Edition - Color Proof Prints, 06-01-2000 (Carton 717, Object 1)
  - Quilt Slides, 2002 (Carton 717, Object 2)
  - Quilt Negatives (Carton 717, Object 3)
  - Flower Negatives #1 - Nos. 19 - 275 (Carton 717, Object 4)
  - Flower Negatives #2 - Nos. 276 - 460 (Carton 717, Object 5)
  - Flower Negatives #3 - No Image Numbers (Carton 717, Object 6)
    - Aerial Photographs, HP Commemorative Posters, Commission to Congressional Committee (Map-folder 718)
    - Maps, NRA Golden Eagle Poster (Map-folder 719)
  - Aerial Photographs, HP Commemorative Posters, Commission to Congressional Committee (Map-folder 718)
  - Maps, NRA Golden Eagle Poster (Map-folder 719)